Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/ wolfgangsegmuller (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

DevOps

Cloud Applications

Docker

Honors-Awards

IBM Corporate Award for IBM Workload Deployer Technologies

Outstanding Technical Achievement Award for Middleware Virtualization Technologies

Publications

CPU demand for web serving: Measurement analysis and dynamic estimation

Sieve Email Filtering: Extension for Notifications

Workload orchestration and optimization for software defined environments

Sieve Email Filtering: Relational Extension

Patents

Integrated virtual infrastructure system

Controlling workload of a computer system through only external monitoring

Dynamically building a set of compute nodes to host the user's workload

Methods and apparatus for discovering data providers satisfying provider queries

Wolfgang Segmuller

Senior Cloud Architect at State Street Technology Research New York City Metropolitan Area

Summary

I led the testing architecture of an OpenStack cloud. Implemented chaos and performance testing and automation for repeatable testing.

I led DevOps education at Research, with 95% of participants would recommend to others. I led security and DevOps development of a service, enabling code check-in to production within 2 hours.

I performed security reviews that found numerous security issues which were then addressed by the development team.

I led architecture, design, and implementation of hypervisor communications, in Java and Groovy in IBM Workload Deployer, released as a product. I received an IBM Corporate Award for this work.

I led the design and implementation of a work profiler, in Java. This helped schedule traffic to backend web servers to prevent overloading the servers.

I created a Bridge scoring application using SPA and server written in Scala. This was well received by my bridge group. https://github.com/thebridsk/bridgescorer

Skills:

Process: Agile, DevOps

Operating Systems: Windows, Linux

Languages: Java, Scala, Python, C, C++, HTML, CSS, JavaScript

Technologies: GraphQL, Facebook React, Swagger Automation: Jenkins, Travis CI, Terraform, Ansible

Runtime: Docker, Kubernetes, VMWare, AWS, IBM Cloud,

OpenStack

Test: TDD, BDD, Behave, PyUnit, JUnit, ScalaTest

Planning: GitHub, ZenHub

Experience

State Street Technology Research Senior Cloud Architect 2018 - Present (5 years) Greater New York City Area

IBM Research Senior Software Engineering, DevOps 2014 - 2018 (4 years) Greater New York City Area

- Architected, designed and implemented a service based on microservices using Agile and DevOps principles and practices written in Python.
- Led the DevOps and Security for the team.
- With the pipeline I developed we were able to deploy to production within 2 hours of making a code change.
- Led the technical team and taught DevOps to research teams.
- Created bootcamps, weekly seminars and provided consultation services.
 95% of the bootcamp participants would recommend the bootcamp to others.

IBM Research Senior Software Engineering, Cloud Systems 2010 - 2013 (3 years) Greater New York City Area

 Architectured, designed, and implemented of the VMSupport layer for monitoring and manipulating hypervisors. This was released in IBM Workload Deployer. Received an IBM Corporate Award for this work.

IBM Research Senior Software Engineering, Application Server 2004 - 2009 (5 years) Greater New York City Area

• Designed and implemented a work profiler, in Java, for measuring resource usage per request, this was used to prevent overloading of backend application servers.

• Developed a log analysis tool verifying proper operation of work profiler.

Education

Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute
Bachelor's degree, Computer Science, Chemistry